Roman Right (Korolev)



roman-right@protonmail.com



linkedin.com/in/roman-right

Summary

I'm a Senior Python Developer/Team Lead with over 10 years of experience in the industry (since 2009). I specialize in databases and storages and have a passion for exploring and working with various database technologies.

I'm proud to be a MongoDB Champion, recognized for my expertise and contributions to the MongoDB community. You can learn more about the MongoDB Champions program here: https://www.mongodb.com/ community/advocacy/.

Here are some things I really enjoy:

- Designing and implementing solutions to real-life problems.
- Exploring and experimenting with new technologies, libraries, and frameworks.
- Sharing knowledge at meetups.
- Contributing to open-source projects.

I have authored the following projects:

Beanie: An asynchronous Python object-document mapper (ODM) for MongoDB.

GitHub: https://github.com/roman-right/beanie

AnnaDB: A next-gen developer-first data store. GitHub: https://github.com/Anna-Team/AnnaDB

Experience

ot Principal Software Engineer

OneTrust

Sep 2021 - Present (1 year 10 months)

My responsibilities included:

- Designing and implementing the architecture.
- Collaborating with specialists from different domains to identify and implement effective solutions.
- Incorporating modern design patterns to enhance performance.
- Collaborating with various teams to facilitate seamless integrations.
- Taking ownership of my projects, prioritizing, and distributing tasks.

The tech stack:

- FastAPI
- MongoDB (Beanie ODM)
- Lambda Functions (Different for different cloud providers)

- Native cloud messaging systems + Kafka

Backend Software Engineer

Teraki

Jun 2019 - Aug 2021 (2 years 3 months)

About the company:

Teraki's mission is to enable personalized and accurate machine learning based applications without a compromise towards 100% safety. It's Al-powered software product operates at the embedded level. Teraki delivers these benefits for automotive and IoT applications (such as drones, robots, smartphones) for which we lower latencies, reduce costs and enhance machine learning accuracy with 10%-30% vs. state-of-the art.

My duties here are:

- REST API and Kafka-based services design and implementation
- Inter-services communication design and implementation
- Databases design

Senior Python Developer

Twyla Al

Feb 2019 - May 2019 (4 months)

Twyla's Canvas platform enables businesses of all sizes to harness the knowledge of human subject matter experts. It provides the ability to design and implement conversational experiences that not only save time and money, but delights users.

Duties:

- Develop web services
- Design applications and databases
- API development

Stack:

aiohttp, flask, sanic, postgres, mongo, redis, RabbitMQ

IT Lead

OSA decentralized (OSA DC)

Feb 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 10 months)

The company provides analytics services. Customers are large retailers and manufacturers. The service uses big data received from the retailer in real time (receipts, assortment matrix, stocks and etc. Tens of millions of records per hour)

Duties:

- System architecture design (databases and applications).
- ETL development
- Internal and external API development (REST)
- Creating microservices (Tornado, aiohttp)
- CI/CD processes
- Coordination of development team

Solution stack:

Python3.6, Tornado, aiohttp, Postgres, ClickHouse, Redis, Apache Spark, RabbitMQ

IT Lead

pplatform

Jan 2016 - Feb 2017 (1 year 2 months)

The company provides targeted advertising services. The project was implemented from scratch.

Duties:

- System architecture design (databases and applications).
- API development (REST)
- Creating microservices (Tornado)
- CI/CD processes
- Coordination of development team

Solution stack:

Python3, Tornado, Postgres, Redis

Python developer

Mail.ru Group

Aug 2015 - Dec 2015 (5 months)

Development of health.mail.ru backend. Integration of large geo and medical services into the system.

Duties:

- API development (REST)
- Backend development (Django)
- Integrations with external services
- ETL development

Solution stack:

Python2.7, Django, MySQL, OSM

PURRAJ Full Stack Developer

OORRAA

Feb 2015 - Aug 2015 (7 months)

Prototypes development in marketplace

Duties:

- Integrations with external services
- Backend development (Django)
- Frontend development (React, Backbone)
- API development (REST)

Solution stack:

Python2.7, Django, Postgres, React, Backbone

Python Developer

Jan 2009 - Feb 2015 (6 years 2 months) Development of backend and frontend

Duties:

- API development (REST)
- Backend development (Django, Flask)
- Frontend development (React, Backbone, Angular)
- Admin pages development
- ETL development
- CI/CD processes

Education



Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU)

Mathematics 2007 - 2013

Skills

Open-Source Development • Python • Web Development • Databases • Software Development • Project Management • Agile Methodologies • Programming • SQL • MySQL